Koh Tachai is a beautiful Thai island.
达柴岛是泰国一座美丽的岛屿。
Sandy beaches, blue sea, plenty of sunshine; paradise ... and that's why you can't go there!
有着沙滩海滩、蓝色的大海和充足的阳光；简直是天堂......而这就是你不能去那里的原因！
It's part of the Similan National Park, which attracts too many holidaymakers and divers and this has been causing problems.
它是斯米兰国家公园的一部分，这里吸引了太多的度假者和潜水者，这已经引发了一些问题。
According to Tunya Netithammakul, Director General of the Department of National Parks, Wildlife and Plants Conservation, "we have to close it to allow the rehabilitation of the environment both on the island and in the sea without being disturbed by tourism activities before the damage is beyond repair."
据泰国国家公园、野生动物和植物保护部总干事吾亚·内蒂坦玛库尔称，“我们必须关闭这个岛屿，以便在损害无法挽回之前，让岛上和海洋的环境在不受旅游活动干扰的情况下得到恢复。”
Many beauty spots around the world have paid a high price for their popularity.
世界上许多旅游景点都因其受欢迎程度而付出了高昂的代价。
The Phi Phi Islands, also in Thailand, came under pressure after the movie The Beach, starring Leonardo Di Caprio, was filmed there.
同样位于泰国的皮皮岛，在莱昂纳多·迪卡普里奥主演的电影《海滩》在那里拍摄后，也面临着压力。
The boom in tourism might have been good news for local traders but not for the coral reefs, destroyed by boats' anchors and pollution from motorboats.
旅游业的繁荣对当地商人来说可能是个好消息，但对珊瑚礁来说却并非如此，珊瑚礁被船只的锚和摩托艇造成的污染所破坏。
Far away, in Ecuador, the Galapagos Archipelago, a World Heritage Site, is famous for a unique ecosystem that inspired Charles Darwin to write his Theory of Evolution.
在遥远的厄瓜多尔，作为世界遗产的加拉帕戈斯群岛，以其独特的生态系统而闻名，这个生态系统启发查尔斯·达尔文写出了他的《进化论》。
There's a concern about what can be taken away — it's illegal to buy souvenirs made from animal parts or native wood — but also about the invasive species brought in by visitors.
人们不仅担心有什么东西会被带走——购买由动物器官或当地木材制成的纪念品是违法的——而且还担心游客带来的入侵物种。
A researcher has warned about the new types of ants arriving all the time travelling in aircraft, boats and even tourists' luggage.
一位研究人员警告说，总是有新型蚂蚁通过飞机、船只甚至游客的行李进入这里。
Maybe we humans are the most threatening of all invasive species.
也许我们人类是所有入侵物种中最具威胁性的。
We tend to leave rubbish everywhere and build infrastructure in some areas that can't support it.
我们往往会把垃圾扔得到处都是，还会在一些无法承受基础设施的地区修建它们。
The question we should ask ourselves is: would we agree to give up visiting these paradises for a while in order to allow them to regenerate and preserve them for future generations or as we only live once, should we go wherever we like and enjoy it while it lasts?
我们应该问自己的问题是：为了让这些天堂般的地方恢复生机，并为子孙后代保护它们，我们是否愿意暂时放弃去这些地方游玩呢？或者，因为我们只活一次，我们是否应该想去哪里就去哪里，在这些地方还存在的时候尽情享受呢？